Heads will roll.
Sleepy Hollow is a fantasy, thriller, mystery film directed by Tim Burton.
Skeptical young detective Ichabod Crane gets transferred to the hamlet of Sleepy Hollow, New York, where he is tasked with
investigating the decapitations of three people – murders the townsfolk attribute to a legendary specter, The Headless Horseman.
Ichabod Crane, played by Johnny Depp.
Katrina Van Tassel, played by Christina Ricci.
Lady Mary Van Tassel / Crone Witch, played by Miranda Richardson.
Baltus Van Tassel, played by Michael Gambon.
Brom Van Brunt, played by Casper Van Dien.
Reverend Steenwyck, played by Jeffrey Jones.
Sleepy Hollow is a 1999 Gothic horror film directed by Tim
Burton from a screenplay by Andrew Kevin Walker.
Co-produced by Paramount Pictures, Mandalay Pictures, Scott Rudin Productions, American Zoetrope, and Tim Burton Productions, it is based on Washington Irving's 1820 short story "The
Legend of Sleepy Hollow", and stars Johnny Depp and Christina Ricci, with Miranda Richardson, Michael Gambon, Casper Van Dien, and Jeffrey Jones in supporting roles.
The plot follows New York City police constable Ichabod Crane (Depp), who is sent to investigate a series of brutal murders in the upstate village of Sleepy
Hollow, where he becomes romantically involved with Katrina Van Tassel (Ricci), the daughter of the richest resident of the town (Gambon).
Sleepy Hollow began development in 1993 at Paramount Pictures, with Kevin Yagher originally
set to direct Andrew Kevin Walker's script as a low-budget slasher film.
Disagreements with Paramount resulted in Yagher being demoted to prosthetic
makeup designer, and Burton was hired to direct in June 1998.
Filming took place from November 1998 to May 1999.
The film was an international co-production
between Germany and the United States.
Sleepy Hollow had its world premiere at Mann's Chinese Theatre on November 17, 1999, and
was released in the United States on November 19, by Paramount Pictures.
It received positive reviews from critics, and grossed $207 million.
It won the Academy Award for Best Art Direction.
The film explores themes of small town, steampunk,
police detective, new york state, skeptic.
The tone is dark and mind_bending and intense.